Guide to the Joseph Bruchac Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- April 1999 Acquisition, 1977-1998; 10 linear feet (10 boxes)
  - Subject Files
    - Mailing request, 1994 (Box 107)
    - Mankiller, Wilma P. Cherokee Nation, 1991 (Box 107)
    - Margolis, Dick, 1991-1992 (Box 107)
    - Media coverage, 1992 (Box 107)
    - Mexican/Central American writers, 1991 (Box 107)
    - Morningstar Foundation/Suzan Harjo, 1991-1992 (Box 107)
    - Myrin Institute, undated (Box 107)
    - NADP House List, 1995 (Box 108)
    - National Congress of American Indians, 1991 (Box 108)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities, undated (Box 108)
    - Native American Authors Booklist, 1990-93 (Box 108)
    - Native American Authors Distribution Project
      - Native American Authors Distribution, 1987 (Box 108)
      - NAADP, 1985-1992; 3 (Box 108)
      - Magazine Article, 1992 (Box 108)
      - NAADP. Publishers, 1997 (Box 108)
      - NAADP. List Summer, 1990-1991 (Box 108)
      - Native American catalogues, 1977-1997; 2 (Box 108)
      - Native American Distribution, 1988 (Box 108)
      - Native American Distribution Book List, 1986-1989 (Box 108)
    - Native Indian/Inunit photographers, 1992 (Box 108)
    - Native Nations, 1991 (Box 108)
    - Native Peoples Magazine, 1991 (Box 108)
    - Native Playwrights Newsletter, 1992 (Box 108)
    - Native presses, 1990 (Box 108)
    - Native writers requesting information, 1990-1992 (Box 108)
    - Native writers: phone numbers and addresses, 1989-1990 (Box 108)
    - Native Writers Circle, 1992 (Box 108)
    - Natura Cultura, 1992 (Box 108)
    - New Mexico Steering Committee Meeting, 1991 (Box 108)
    - New Native Writing Awards, 1992 (Box 108)
    - New Native Writers: rejections, 1992 (Box 108)
    - New World Library, 1993 (Box 108)
    - Newsletter NWC, 1992-1993 (Box 108)
    - Newspaper articles and magazines, 1992 (Box 108)
    - New York Historical Society, 1991-1992 (Box 109)
    - New York Times Foundation (Returning the Gift), 1990-1996 (Box 109)
    - North American Native Authors Catalog, 1994-1997; 3 (Box 109)
    - "N", 1991 (Box 109)
    - OCCE August Statement, 1992 (Box 109)
    - OCCE: financial statement, 1992 (Box 109)
    - Oklahoma Humanities Foundation, 1991 (Box 109)
    - Oklahoma Tribal Councils, 1991 (Box 109)
    - Onondaga Indian School. Audrey Shenandoah, 1991 (Box 109)
    - The Paul Foundation. Fred Bay, 1992 (Box 109)
    - PEN American Center, 1991 (Box 109)
    - Pepsico, undated (Box 109)
    - Personal log and notes for RTG, 1991 (Box 109)
    - Phillip Morris, 1991 (Box 109)
    - Poetry East, 1991 (Box 109)
    - Poetry Society of America, 1991-1992 (Box 109)
    - Poets and Writers/RTG, 1992 (Box 109)
    - Pow-wows, 1984-1995; 11 (Box 109)
    - Program of conference, 1992 (Box 109)
    - Public House Bookshop, 1990 (Box 109)
    - Publishers list: Returning the Gift, undated (Box 109)
    - Publishers, 1991 (Box 109)
    - Reader's Digest Fund/Lila Wallace, 1991-1992 (Box 109)
    - Rediscovering the History of the Americas: Clery and Laity Concerned, 1991 (Box 109)
    - Rejections, 1990-1991 (Box 109)
    - Returning the Gift
      - Returning the Gift. Grants, 1990-1991 (Box 109)
      - Returning the Gift. Relevant articles, 1991; 4 (Box 110)
      - Returning the Gift, undated; 5 (Box 110)
      - Returning the Gift. Resumes: Steering Committee, 1990 (Box 110)
      - Returning the Gift. Project description and rationale, 1990 (Box 110)
      - Returning the Gift. Request for support, 1991 (Box 110)
      - Returning the Gift. Reports, 1990 (Box 110)
    - Revard, Carter, 1990 (Box 110)
    - Richter Productions, 1990-1991 (Box 110)
    - Rockefeller Foundation, 1992 (Box 110)
    - Rush mailing, 1993-1994 (Box 110)
    - Russia, 1991 (Box 110)
    - Sackler Foundation, 1991 (Box 110)
    - Sail Returning the Gift Issue, 1992 (Box 110)
    - Saranac Lake Meeting, 1990 (Box 110)
    - Scholarships, 1992 (Box 110)
    - Sequoyah Magazine, Belgium, 1991 (Box 110)
    - Small grant request, 1992 (Box 110)
    - Small press article, 1990 (Box 110)
    - Smeal, Henry, 1992 (Box 110)
    - Smithsonian, 1991 (Box 110)
    - Snow Memorial Trust, 1991 (Box 110)
    - South and Meso-American Indian Information Center (SAITC), 1991 (Box 110)
    - Snowbird Publishing, 1991-1992 (Box 110)
    - Southwest Bell application, 1990-1991 (Box 110)
    - Sponsoring, undated (Box 110)
    - Steering Committee; letters to, 1990-1991 (Box 110)
    - Steering Committee; support people, possible, 1989-1990 (Box 110)
    - Steering Committee, 1990-1991 (Box 110)
    - Tankel, Claire, 1990-1991 (Box 110)
    - Tainos Del Norte (La Concha), 1990 (Box 110)
    - Texaco, 1990-1991 (Box 111)
    - Threshold Foundation; Jeffrey Bronfman, 1990 (Box 111)
    - The Tides Foundation, 1991 (Box 111)
    - Troy, Timothy, 1991-1992 (Box 111)
    - University of Arizona Press, 1988-1989 (Box 111)
    - University of Minnesota Press, 1988 (Box 111)
    - University of Nebraska Press, 1985-1986 (Box 111)
    - University of Oklahoma, 1991-1992 (Box 111)
    - Vizenor, Gerald, 1992 (Box 111)
    - Walk Across America, 1991 (Box 111)
    - Watson, Mary Jo; assistant to dean, undated (Box 111)
    - Welburn, Ron, 1992 (Box 111)
    - William Yellow Robe, 1991 (Box 111)
    - Wingspread, 1989-1990; 2 (Box 111)
    - Writers: letters and information packets, 1992 (Box 111)
    - Writers Voice, 1992 (Box 111)
    - Writers invited to festival, 1991 (Box 111)
  - Subject Files
    - Anthology acceptances and rejections (RTG), 1993 (Box 111)
    - Anthology (University of Arizona). Consent to publish forms, 1994 (Box 111)
    - Anthology (RTG). University of Arizona Press, 1993-1994; 3 (Box 111)
    - American Indian Community House, 1991 (Box 111)
    - Birchfield, Don, 1993-1996 (Box 111)
    - Book awards, 1992-1996; 3 (Box 111)
    - Caldwell, Kim, 1997 (Box 111)
    - Dodge Foundation, 1992-1996 (Box 111)
    - Fiction finalists, 1993 (Box 112)
    - First Book awards, 1994 (Box 112)
    - First Book, 1995 (Box 112)
    - First Book finalists, 1995 (Box 112)
    - First Book awards, 1996-1998; 4 (Box 112)
    - First Nations authors, 1991 (Box 112)
    - Francis, Lee, 1992-1994 (Box 112)
    - Hobson, Geary, 1993 (Box 112)
    - Invitees, 1991 (Box 112)
    - Kellogg Anthology, 1992-1993; 7 (Box 112)
    - Letters from Native American writers, 1993 (Box 112)
    - Membership list, 1993-1994 (Box 112)
    - Metoxen, Kenneth Brickman. Collection of poems, 1995 (Box 112)
    - Moccasin Telegraph, 1993-1997; 6 (Box 112)
    - Native Writers Circle. Mailing list, 1993; 3 (Box 112)
    - Native Writers Circle, 1995 (Box 112)
    - Native Writers Circle Newsletter, 1992-1993; 4 (Box 112)
    - Native Playwrights Newsletter, 1993-1994 (Box 113)
    - North American Native Authors Award, 1995 (Box 113)
    - North Country Community College, 1993 (Box 113)
    - Oklahoma Festival, 1993 (Box 113)
    - Palmer, Gus, 1994 (Box 113)
    - Reclaiming The Vision, undated (Box 113)
    - Red-Eagle, Philip H., 1993-1994; 3 (Box 113)
    - Request For catalogue, 1989-1991 (Box 113)
    - Returning The Gift
      - Akwekon, 1992 (Box 113)
      - Articles, 1992-1993; 3 (Box 113)
      - Awards, 1994 (Box 113)
      - Canada En'owkin Centre, 1996 (Box 113)
      - Deficit repayment, 1993 (Box 113)
      - Directory, 1993 (Box 113)
      - Evaluations/Letters, 1991 (Box 113)
      - Lifetime Achievement Award, 1994-1995 (Box 113)
      - Neah Bay, Washington, 1993-1994 (Box 113)
      - Oneida, 1995 (Box 113)
      - Photos by Jolene Rickard, 1993 (Box 113)
      - Residencies, 1992 (Box 113)
      - Unidentified, 1992-1998; 5 (Box 113)
    - Talk Transcripts
      - Armstrong, Jeanette, 1993 (Box 114)
      - Brant, Beth, 1993 (Box 114)
      - Bush, Barney, 1993 (Box 114)
      - Henson, Lance, 1993 (Box 114)
      - Hogan, Linda, 1993 (Box 114)
      - Jacobs, Alex, 1993 (Box 114)
      - Littlebird, Harold, 1993 (Box 114)
      - Morgan, Kelly, undated (Box 114)
      - Moses, Daniel David, undated (Box 114)
      - Silko, Leslie Marmon, 1993 (Box 114)
      - Sioui, Eleanor, undated (Box 114)
      - Tritt, Lincoln, 1993 (Box 114)
      - Woody, Elizabeth, 1993 (Box 114)
      - Zapeda, Ofelia, 1993 (Box 114)
      - Tate, Joe Dale, 1992 (Box 114)
      - Transcripts: Diana's, undated (Box 114)
      - Winn Starr, 1997 (Box 114)
      - Wordcraft Circle of Native Writers & Storytellers
        - Wordcraft Circle of Native Writers & Storytellers, 1997-1998; 4 (Box 114)
        - Other authors, 1995 (Box 114)
        - Letters from Lee, 1992-1993 (Box 114)
        - Unidentified, undated (Box 114)
      - Videocassettes
        - "Native American Identity: Wordcraft Circle of Native American Writers," Native America Leadership Program, Lansing Community College, length 28_30, 1994; YCALMSS740_0010; 1; 00:28:56 (Box 115, Item barcode 39002102349009)
        - "Returning the Gift," tape 1 of 1, 1992 July 8; YCALMSS740_0011; 1; 01:58:27 (Box 115, Item barcode 39002102349017)
        - "Returning the Gift," tape 1 of 1, 1992 July 10; YCALMSS740_0012; 1; 01:41:01 (Box 115, Item barcode 39002102349025)
        - "Returning the Gift," tape 1 of 2, 1992 July 9; YCALMSS740_0013; 1; 00:57:55 (Box 115, Item barcode 39002102349033)
        - "Returning the Gift," tape 2 of 2, 1992 July 9; YCALMSS740_0014; 1; 01:26:53 (Box 115, Item barcode 39002102349041)
        - "Returning the Gift," tape 1 of 2, 1992 July 7; YCALMSS740_0015; 1; 00:47:53 (Box 115, Item barcode 39002102349058)
        - "Returning the Gift," tape 2 of 2, 1992 July 7; YCALMSS740_0016; 1; 01:05:28 (Box 115, Item barcode 39002102349066)
        - Related notes and correspondence, 1992-1993; 2 (Box 115)
          The material is related specifically to the audiovisual material.
      - Audiocassettes
        - Planning meeting for a Festival of Native American Writers, (1 of 7 audiocassettes), 1990 May 29-31; 1 (Box 115, Item barcode 39002091243031)
        - Planning meeting for a Festival of Native American Writers, (2 of 7 audiocassettes), 1990 May 29-31; 1 (Box 115, Item barcode 39002091243049)
        - Planning meeting for a Festival of Native American Writers, (3 of 7 audiocassettes), 1990 May 29-31; 1 (Box 115, Item barcode 39002091243056)
        - Planning meeting for a Festival of Native American Writers, (4 of 7 audiocassettes), 1990 May 29-31; 1 (Box 115, Item barcode 39002091243064)
        - Planning meeting for a Festival of Native American Writers, (5 of 7 audiocassettes), 1990 May 29-31; 1 (Box 115, Item barcode 39002091243072)
        - Planning meeting for a Festival of Native American Writers, (6 of 7 audiocassettes), 1990 May 29-31; 1 (Box 115, Item barcode 39002091243080)
        - Planning meeting for a Festival of Native American Writers, (7 of 7 audiocassettes), 1990 May 29-31; 1 (Box 115, Item barcode 39002091243098)
- July 2006 Acquisition, 1961-2006; 29.63 linear feet (31 boxes)
  Organized into three subseries: Correspondence, arranged chronologically, most 1997-2005; Writings, arranged in three subseries, Writings by Bruchac, Writings of Other Native American Authors, and Writings of Others; and Bookings, arranged chronologically, 1990s-2000s.
  Correspondence contains letters from Bruchac to his parents, Joseph and Marion Bruchac, 1961-1984, followed by other correspondence, 1997-2005. Writings include materials relating to books, most published during 1990s-2000s. Bookings contains materials relating to storytelling and other appearances by Bruchac. Additional materials relating to writings and storytelling are in the Correspondence series.
  - Correspondence
    - Bruchac, Joseph, and Bruchac, Marion, 1961-1984; 2 (Box 116)
      Letters from Bruchac to his parents
    - Other correspondence, 1997; 8 (Box 116)
    - Other correspondence, 1997-1998; 7 (Box 116)
    - Other correspondence, 2001-2002; 7 (Box 117)
    - Other correspondence, 2003-2004; 8 (Box 117)
    - Email printouts, 2001-2003; 6 (Box 118)
    - Email printouts, 2003-2005; 9 (Box 118)
  - Writings
    - Writings by Bruchac
      - Darby Creek
        - The Warriors, undated; 3 (Box 119)
        - The Warriors, first drafts, 2002 November (Box 119)
      - Dial Books
        - A Codetalker's Story
          - Drafts, undated; 2 (Box 119)
          - Junior Library Guild resource catalog, 2003 (Box 119)
          - First major revision, 2003 (Box 119)
          - Drafts, undated (Box 119)
          - First draft, undated (Box 119)
          - Drafts, undated (Box 119)
          - Galleys, 2004 (Box 119)
          - Drafts, undated; 3 (Box 119)
          - Bibliography, undated (Box 119)
          - Chronology, undated (Box 119)
          - Wordcraft Circle, 2002 (Box 119)
          - Komanche, 1999 (Box 119)
          - 3rd Marine Division, undated (Box 119)
          - Fact sheet, undated (Box 120)
          - Dictionary, undated (Box 120)
          - Articles, undated (Box 120)
          - Zonnie, Gorman, undated (Box 120)
          - Questions, undated (Box 120)
          - Harry Walters, undated (Box 120)
          - Lauri Hornik, undated (Box 120)
          - Pacific Maps, undated (Box 120)
        - How Chipmunk Got His Stripes, undated (Box 120)
        - Pushing Up the Sky, galley proofs, undated (Box 120)
        - Raccoon's Last Race, 2003-2005 (Box 120)
        - Turtle's Race with Beaver, 2002; 2 (Box 120)
        - Wabi, undated (Box 120)
        - Wabi revisions, 2005 (Box 120)
        - Wabi, final, 2005 (Box 120)
        - Wabi manuscript draft, undated (Box 120)
        - The Winter People
          - Map, undated (Box 120)
          - Draft, undated; 4 (Box 120)
          - Final draft, 2001 (Box 120)
      - Harcourt Brace
        - Catalogues, 1999-2002; 2 (Box 121)
        - Educational, 1999 (Box 121)
        - Victoria Tisch, 2000 (Box 121)
        - Paula Wiseman, 2000 (Box 121)
        - Correspondence, royalties, and drafts, 1999 (Box 121)
        - Royalties, etc., 1998 (Box 121)
        - Letters, 1998 September (Box 121)
        - Hungry Giant, draft, undated; 2 (Box 121)
        - Pocahontas (Box 121)
          - First draft, undated (Box 121)
          - Second draft, undated (Box 121)
          - Drafts, undated; 2 (Box 121)
          - Revision, 2002 (Box 121)
        - Sacagawea
          - Manuscript, 2 (Box 121)
          - Copy to Shoshones, 1999 (Box 121)
          - Final draft, 1999 September 27 (Box 121)
          - Harcourt, drafts, 1999; 2 (Box 121)
          - Correspondence and addresses, undated (Box 121)
          - Draft, 1998 (Box 121)
          - Draft, undated (Box 122)
          - Eileen Charbonneau, undated (Box 122)
          - Paula's edits, 1999 (Box 122)
          - Contract, undated (Box 122)
          - Reviews, 2000 (Box 122)
          - Draft, undated (Box 122)
          - Proofs, undated (Box 122)
        - Squanto
          - Squanto's Story, 1998 November (Box 122)
          - Tisquantum's Journey, undated (Box 122)
          - Squanto's Journey, 1999 (Box 122)
          - Reviews, undated (Box 122)
          - Squanto, undated (Box 122)
          - Marge Bruchac research, 1998 (Box 122)
          - Research, undated; 5 (Box 122)
          - Proofs, 1999; 2 (Box 122)
      - HarperCollins
        - Breakfast Serials
          - The Black Squirrel. Newspapers, 2000 (Box 123)
          - The Black Squirrel. Detroit News, 2000 (Box 123)
          - The Breakfast Serials information packet, 1999 (Box 123)
          - The Black Squirrel .Correspondence, 1999 (Box 123)
          - The Black Squirrel. Drafts, 1999, undated; 2 (Box 123)
          - The Black Squirrel. Breakfast Serials, 2001 (Box 123)
          - The Black Squirrel. Final, Amy Griffin edit, 1999 September (Box 123)
          - The Black Squirrel. dDrafts, undated (Box 123)
          - The Black Squirrel. Second draft, undated (Box 123)
        - The Dark Pond
          - Manuscripts, 2001-2002; 4 (Box 123)
          - Uncorrected proof, 2004 (Box 123)
          - Illustrations, undated (Box 123)
          - Manuscripts, undated; 3 (Box 123)
        - Return of Skeleton Man
          - Final manuscript, 2005 (Box 124)
          - First drafts, undated (Box 124)
          - Manuscript drafts, undated; 2 (Box 124)
          - Second draft, undated (Box 124)
        - Skeleton Man
          - Uncorrected proofs, undated (Box 124)
          - Revision, 2000 September (Box 124)
          - Junior Literary Guild, 2001 (Box 124)
          - Correspondence and catalog, 2001 (Box 124)
          - Contract (Box 124)
          - Alex Reid, 2000 (Box 124)
          - Draft, 1999 (Box 124)
          - Final, 1999 September 7 (Box 124)
          - Page proofs, 2001 (Box 124)
          - Second draft, 2000 (Box 124)
          - Copy edited, final manusctipt, undated (Box 124)
          - Edited for revisions, undated (Box 124)
        - Whisper in the Dark
          - Uncorrected proof, 2005 (Box 124)
          - Manuscript, 2004 (Box 124)
          - First drafts, 2003 July-August (Box 124)
          - Galleys, 2004 (Box 124)
          - Manuscript, 2005 (Box 124)
      - Lee & Low, Inc.
        - Code Talkers, 2000; 2 (Box 125)
        - Crazy Horse
          - Media, 1999-2005 (Box 125)
          - Reviews, 1999-2001; 2 (Box 125)
          - Galley proof, undated (Box 125)
        - Jim Thorpe's Bright Path
          - Revisions, 2002 (Box 125)
          - First draft, 2005 (Box 125)
          - Drafts, etc., undated; 4 (Box 125)
          - Lee & Low illustrations, 2004 (Box 125)
          - [Galleys], undated (Box 125)
      - National Geographic Books
        - "Bombardment," draft, undated (Box 126)
        - Hiawatha and Megissogwon, galley proof, undated (Box 126)
        - Children's books catalog, 2001 (Box 126)
        - The Navajo Long Walk, drafts, 2000; 2 (Box 126)
        - Unidentified, undated; 4 (Box 126)
        - Trail of Tears, Paths of Beauty
          - Drafts and galley proof, undated; 6 (Box 126)
          - J. T. Garrett, undated (Box 126)
          - Orders, 2004 (Box 126)
          - Barbara Brownell, 2000 (Box 126)
          - Tahlequah, 1999 December (Box 126)
          - Kit Carson Campaign, undated (Box 127)
          - Navajo: internet research, 2000 (Box 127)
          - Maps, undated (Box 127)
          - Drafts, undated; 2 (Box 127)
          - Barbara Brownell, 1999 (Box 127)
          - Contract, 1999 (Box 127)
          - Cherokee artists, 1998 (Box 127)
          - Cherokee removal, Journals 1837-38, undated (Box 127)
          - Cherokee timeline, undated (Box 127)
          - Drafts, undated; 6 (Box 127)
          - Rebecca Barnes, 2000 (Box 127)
          - Hobson comments, 2000 (Box 127)
          - Captions, 2000 (Box 127)
          - Harry Walters comments, 2000 (Box 127)
          - Chapter one, 2000 (Box 127)
          - Revisions, 2000 (Box 127)
          - Drafts, galley proofs, notes, and correspondence, undated; 3 (Box 127)
          - Drafts, galley proofs, notes, and correspondence, undated; 2 (Box 128)
          - Map, undated (Box 128)
          - Outline, undated (Box 128)
          - Photo outline, undated (Box 128)
          - Children's books catalogs, 2000 (Box 128)
      - Parabola
        - "Dying", undated (Box 128)
        - "The Fool Issue", 2001 (Box 128)
        - "Heart", 2001 (Box 128)
        - "Prison", 2003 (Box 128)
        - "War", 2002 (Box 128)
      - Scholastic (Box 128)
        - Geronimo
          - Uncorrected proof and slides, 2006 (Box 128)
          - Book proposal, undated (Box 128)
          - Drafts, undated; 5 (Box 128)
          - Final draft, 2005 September 14 (Box 128)
          - Apaches at Carlisle, undated (Box 128)
          - Drafts, undated; 3 (Box 129)
        - "Held by the Hills," revised, 2000 February 8 (Box 129)
        - "Held by the Hills," editor's comments, undated (Box 129)
        - Hidden Roots
          - Draft, 2001 (Box 129)
          - Scholastic edits, undated (Box 129)
          - Edited manuscript, 2003 June (Box 129)
          - Galley proofs, 2003 July (Box 129)
          - Line edits and cover, 2003 (Box 129)
          - Drafts, 2001 (Box 129)
          - Author visit list, 2000 (Box 129)
          - Catalog, 1999 (Box 129)
        - "The Journal of Jesse Smoke"
          - Amy Griffin, 2000 (Box 129)
          - Discussion, 2001 (Box 129)
          - Drafts, 2000 (Box 129)
          - First Draft, 1999-2000 (Box 129)
          - Drafts, 2000, undated; 2 (Box 130)
        - "My Name is America", 1999 (Box 130)
        - Seasons of the Circle, drafts and galley proofs, 2000-2001; 4 (Box 130)
    - Writings of Other Native American Authors
      - Armstrong, Jeannette C. Whispering in Shadows, 2000 (Theytus Books), undated (Box 131)
      - Beer, Jim and Hunt, Rick, undated (Box 131)
      - Big Jim, Fred, 1993 (Box 131)
      - Blaeser, Kimberly M. The Absentee Indian, 2002 (Box 131)
      - Blaeser. Ojibwe Anthology, 2004 (Box 131)
      - Bushyhead, Robert H. Yonder Mountain, 1998 (Box 131)
      - Chin, David, 1999 (Box 131)
      - Chute, Bob, 2001 (Box 131)
      - Coke, Allison Hedge. Rock Ghost, Willow, Deer, undated (Box 131)
      - Eagle, Adam Fortunate
        See: Fortunate Eagle, Adam
      - Edmo, Ed, 2000 (Box 131)
      - Fawcett, Melissa. Oracles, undated; 3 (Box 131)
      - Fawcett, Melissa. Medicine Trail, 1999 (Box 131)
      - Fortunate Eagle, Adam, undated (Box 131)
      - Foxfire, undated (Box 131)
      - Francis, Lee, 1999 (Box 131)
      - Francis, Lee, undated (Box 131)
      - Gansworth, Eric L. Smoke Dancing, 2004 (Box 132)
      - Hebert, Ernest. The Old American, undated (Box 132)
      - Hedge-Coke, Allison Adelle
        See: Coke, Allison Hedge
      - Horn. "Transcendence", undated (Box 132)
      - Kenny, Maurice. In the Time of the Present, 2000 (Box 132)
      - Krapf. "Adam and the Bells", undated (Box 132)
      - Lone Otter, Chief
        See: Treadwell, Don
      - Macintosh, Billie Jane. "Ak-koh-kee", undated (Box 132)
      - "The Memoirs of Princess Red Wing", 1999 (Box 132)
      - Norman, Howard A. The Girl Who Dreamed Only Geese, undated (Box 132)
      - Owens, Lewis. "Tribute to a Native Author", undated (Box 132)
      - Pettigrew, Dawn Karima., 2002 (Box 132)
      - Pettigrew, Dawn Karima. The Marriage of Saints, undated (Box 132)
      - Rayle, James. The Trial of Billy Running Dog, undated (Box 132)
      - Salisbury, Ralph J. "By the Skin of Our Teeth", undated (Box 132)
      - Salisbury, Ralph J. T he Indian Who Bombed Berlin, undated (Box 133)
      - Salisbury, Ralph J. Rainbows of Stone, undated (Box 133)
      - Salisbury, Ralph J. Rainbow of Stone, University of Arizona, 2000 (Box 133)
      - Sarris, Gre. Letter of support of promotion, undated (Box 133)
      - Schmidtke, Carston. "Trickster in a Strange Land", 2003 (Box 133)
      - Smelcer, John E., 2003 (Box 133)
      - [Strong Woman], undated (Box 133)
      - Tantaquidgeon. Oracles, undated; 2 (Box 133)
      - Tantaquidgeon, undated (Box 133)
      - Tingle, Tim, undated (Box 133)
      - Tohe, Laura. No Parole Today (West End Press), 1999 (Box 133)
      - Treadwell, Don. Turtle People, undated (Box 133)
      - Tritt, Lincoln, 2002 (Box 133)
      - Walls, Velma, undated (Box 133)
      - Welburn, Ron, 1992, 1999; 2 (Box 133)
      - Wiseman, Frederick Matthew. "The Last Alliance", undated (Box 134)
      - Yellow Robe, William S., undated (Box 134)
      - Zobel, Melissa Tantaquidgeon
        See: Fawcett, Melissa
        See: Tantaquidgeon
      - Unidentified, undated (Box 134)
    - Writings of Others
      Non-Indian authors for whom Bruchac wrote reviews, blurbs or introductions
      - Amegashi, Kojo, 1998 (Box 134)
      - Baca, Jimmy Santiago. Set This Book On Fire, undated (Box 134)
      - Delventhal, 1995, 1999 (Box 134)
      - Fleck, undated (Box 134)